

# PEERAPAT POCHANAPAN

## **Business Development Manager**

### About Me

Business development manager with extensive experience leading and managing large-scale, complex projects and product development over crossfunctional teams to fulfill clients' objectives and produce revenue; passionate and value-driven with an agile mindset and the capacity to work directly with executives and personnel at all levels of operation with specialization in developing constructive team dynamics.

#### **Expertise**

- Agile Product Development
- Project Management
- Leadership Experience
- Financial Feasibility Planning
- Internet of Things (IoTs)
- Cloud Services
- Smart Cities
- Excel/Google Sheets
- Google analytics
- Power BI
- Miro

### Contact

- Prachachuen Rd, Bangsue, Bangkok 10800
- peerapat.poch@gmail.com
- 065-191-6646 064-525-5522
- in /peerapat-poch

## Experience

### **Business Development Manager**

JAN 2021 - Present

Digital Business Department

National Telecom Public Company Limited (NT)

- Managing the design and implementation of all digital products and services accounted for approximately THB100 million in revenue;
- Spearheading, directing and launching innovative product development to achieve product-market fit via Proof of Concept (PoCs) projects to potential customers;
- Successfully launching a new SaaS product for migrating existing customers with 90% retention rate and increasing revenue from new customers by 20%;
- Acting as partner relationship manager for the product and partner agreement, resulting in over 10 on-shelf commercial products without conflict of business partnership;
- Coordinating relations among key partners, clients and governmental units;
- Developing department working process with Agile method and digital tools for tracking and improving business development processes;
- Leading a team of 5 business development staffs, and mentoring to adapter mindset and innovative thinking; and,
- Leading Digital Policy and Innovation Lab at Ministry of Digital Economy and Society (MDES) to develop digital service policy and collaborate with government organizations.

#### Other positions at NT:

Business Development Lead at Cloud and Big Data Business Department AUG 2020 - DEC 2020  $\,$ 

- Developed product development of new cloud service; and,
- Initiated new product knowledge program for building product champions in sales team to penetrate market and identify potential customers.

# Business Development Lead at Digital Business Department MAY 2017- AUG 2020

- Implemented LoRa technology nationwide coverage for IoT solutions.
- Explored IoT business opportunities and implemented 15 new solutions to customers and local governors

### Education

Ladkrabang, Thailand

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering University of Michigan, USA	2015 - 2017
Bachelor of Laws (First Class Honors) Chulalongkorn University, Thailand	2018 - 2021
Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics Engineering (First Class Honors; Rank 1 of 145) King Mongkut's Insitute of Technology	2010 - 2014